Emily Dokken

Portland, OR Senior QA Engineer | Fullstack Web Developer 503 913 6888 dokkenemily@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/emdok emilydokken.com

Profile

Senior QA Engineer turned fullstack web developer leveraging ability to critically problem solve and locate issues within code to build better products for an intuitive user experience. Recently earned a certificate in full stack web development from the University of Oregon Coding Bootcamp, with newly developed skills in Javascript, CSS, React.js, MongoDB, SQL, Express, and Node.js. Known as someone who is vehement about writing DRY intuitive code who loves a challenge as well as developing apps with mobile-first design in mind and well organized databases.

Skills

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap, ReactJS, MaterialUI

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, Handlebars, Mongoose, Sequelize, GraphQL

QA: Postman, Cypress, TestRail, Automation, Manual Testing, Test Case Development

Awards

Instrument 2021

AllCo Award for Excellence in Effort

Squarespace 2016

Spotlight Award for Excellence in Customer Service

University of Idaho 2011

Outstanding Senior Design Award

Education

University of Oregon, 2022

FullStack Web Development Certificate

Epicodus, 2017

Introduction to Programming

University of Idaho, 2011

Bachelor of Science, Virtual Technology & Design

Work Experience

Instrument LLC, 2020 - Present - Sr. QA Engineer

- · Write & Maintain clear test cases in TestRail
- · Execute Manual Regression & Feature Specific tests
- Build Postman Test Suite for testing API's
- · Develop Cypress.js automated UI integration test suite
- · Collaborate in Agile Development environment

Squarespace, 2015 - 2020- QA Tester II / Sr. Advisor QA Tester II

- · Create & Oversee Test Plans
- · Perform Exploratory, Regression, & Accessibility testing
- · Automate Test Scripts
- · Collaborate with Engineering & Project stakeholders
- · Manage Project Teams of 2 or more people

Sr. Advisor

- · Respond to customer submitted live chat & email
- · Identify & communicate system issues to engineering
- · Maintain high level of product knowledge
- · Train new hires & provide constructive feedback
- · Present Webinars for new customers
- · Examine and update community forum

Dokken Implement, 2016 - 2020 - Web Designer

- · Curate, design, & build Squarspace websites
- · Maintain client relationships

U.S. Outdoor Store, 2013 - 2015 - Copywriter

- · Photograph products for E-commerce website
- · Modify Images using Adobe Photoshop
- · Write & Edit product descriptions
- · Edit & Film product videos using Adobe Premiere
- · Participate in strategic marketing meetings